

MOHAMAD AGUNG SAPUTRA

+625298834626 | agungsaputraofficial@gmail.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/agungsaputra14/ | https://github.com/itsAgungSaputra | https://www.behance.net/itsagungsaputra

Gorontalo, Indonesia

Active 8th semester Information Systems student at Universitas Negeri Gorontalo, with 4 years of programming experience and a continuous learning mindset, seeks to deepen knowledge and tackle new challenges that will propel career growth and provide valuable experiences. Known for creativity, adaptability to new environments, and effective communication skills. A relatively new entrant into the world of graphic design, passionate about the field and committed to continuous improvement.

Work Experiences

Smart Data Integrasi - Gorontalo, Indonesia

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

Front-End Developer | Internship

Smart Data Integrasi is a company that specializes in web development. The company has contributed to the creation of websites and applications for several government agencies in Gorontalo.

Contributed as a Front-End Developer in developing the official website of North Gorontalo Regency, which provides all
information and news about North Gorontalo Regency.

Freelance - Gorontalo, Indonesia

Apr 2020 - Present

Front-End Developer

High school years transitioning to college years saw dedication to Front-End Development, significantly enhancing experience and skill set.

- Contributed as a Front-End Developer in creating the website for new student registration at SMK Negeri 1 Limboto.
- Contributed as a Front-End Developer in creating the website application for the information management and tuition payment system(SIMIKOM) at SD LABORATORIUM Universitas Negeri Gorontalo.
- Contributed as a Front-End Developer in creating the website for the New Student Orientation (PKKMB) of the Department of Informatics Engineering at Universitas Negeri Gorontalo.
- Contributed as a Front-End Developer in creating a web application for thesis exam verification for the Department of Informatics Engineering at Universitas Negeri Gorontalo.

SAShop Gorontalo - Gorontalo, Indonesia

May 2024 - June 2024

Graphic Designer | Internship

SAShop Gorontalo is a clothing and personal care store based in Gorontalo, Indonesia. They offer a wide variety of fashionable clothing items, including dresses, tops, bottoms, and accessories, for both men and women. Additionally, they carry a range of personal care products, such as skincare, makeup, and hair care products.

• Developed engaging Instagram content for SAShop Gorontalo as a Graphic Designer.

Social Economic Accelerator Lab at Cluster Coding Factory (Sekawan Media) - Malang, Indonesia

Sep 2024 - Dec 2024

Front-End Developer, Quality Control | Internship

Sekawan Media is an IT company focused on developing applications and websites. Founded in 2013, Sekawan Media has provided top-notch solutions to hundreds of clients from various industries..

- Contributed as a Front-End Developer in the development of the "ETIAMS" web application, an internal audit management system application used by one of the BUMN companies in Indonesia.
- Contributed as a Front-End Developer and Quality Control in the development of the "Twintech Precision DCR" web application, a Digital Controlling & Reporting application used by PT. Twintech Precision.
- Contributed as a Front-End Developer in the development of the "Timah SSO" web application, an application used by one of the BUMN companies, PT. Timah.
- Contributed as a Front-End Developer and Quality Control in the development of the "TeAMS (Tomori electronic Audit Management System)" web application, an audit management application used by the Joint Operating Body (JOB) Pertamina-Medco E&P Tomori Sulawesi.

Education Level

Universitas Negeri Gorontalo - Gorontalo

Aug 2021 - Present

Undergraduate in Information Systems, GPA: 3.73/4.00

• Won the IT SOFTWARE competition at Pekan Kreativitas Pemuda Indonesia 2022 as the favorite champion held in Gorontalo.

Universitas Brawijaya - Malang

Aug 2023 - Dec 2023

Undergraduate in Information Systems | Student Exchange, GPA: 3.60/4.00

- Served as a Leader in the UX design project for the mental health app "Riliv", employing the Heuristic Evaluation method in the User Experience and Interface Evaluation course.
- Contributed as a UI/UX Designer in the UI/UX design project for the mobile application "NgeKostinAja" a cost-finding app, in

- the User Experience Design course.
- Led a project team for the UX design of a mobile sports game, "EA SPORTS FC," conducting usability testing by preparing task scenarios and GEQ (Game Experience Questionnaire) instruments for the course of User Experience and Interface Evaluation.
- Contributed as a Front-End Developer in the project assignment to create a webpage for the tourism website "Wonderful Hulonthalo" in the Human-Computer Interaction course.

Organisational Experience

KSL UNG - Gorontalo Nov 2021 - Present

Programming Division Member

KSL (Kelompok Studi Linux) UNG is an organization dedicated to the study of Linux in Universitas Negeri Gorontalo. We specialize in exploring various aspects of Linux, including programming with a focus on software development, networking with an emphasis on network systems, and multimedia with a focus on design and photography.

- Contributed as a Front-End Developer in creating a website for new candidate registration for the Kelompok Studi Linux, enabling applicants to register online.
- Served as a speaker for the "IT KNOWLEDGE IMPROVEMENT" event, delivering a workshop on Basic Web Programming Introduction using HTML and CSS, held from February 11th to 25th, 2023.

Google Developer Study Clubs UNG - Gorontalo

Sep 2023 - Present

Member of Web Cloud and UI/UX

Google Developer Student Clubs (GDSC) are community groups for students interested in Google developer technologies.

Skills, Achievements & Other Experience

- Language: Indonesian (Active), English (Passive)
- Interest: Front-End Devoleper, Project Manager, Quality Control, Graphic Designer, UI/UX Designer.
- Soft Skills: Communication skills, Problem-solving, Collaborative.
- Technical Skills: PHP, MySQL, Javascript, HTML/CSS, Tailwind, Next JS, React JS, Vite JS, Laravel, Code Igniter, C#, ASP.NET Core, Kotlin, Git, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint), Graphic Design (Adobe Photoshop, Figma, Canva, Capcut), Google Colab, Tableau.
- Hard Skills (2021, 2022): Participated in the Junior Web Developer scheme for the Digitalent Scholarship VSGA.
- Achievements (2023): Pertukaran Mahasiswa Merdeka Batch 3 at Universitas Brawijaya Malang
- Hard Skills (2024): Participated in the Intermediate Computer Operator scheme for the Digitalent Scholarship VSGA.